<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.2//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v12.dtd">

<document>
  <header>
    <title>Apache iBATIS - News</title>
  </header> 
  <body>  

	  <section>
		  <title>Infrastructure Migration Complete!</title>
		  <p>
		  (12 Feb 2005) Well, it took a little longer than expected, but we've successfully migrated the entire
       iBATIS project to Apache infrastructure. Now that we have our SVN repository again, I've spent most of the day clearing
       out some overdue JIRA issues. I'll be doing a maintenance release (2.0.9b) within a day or two in order to
       keep you all up and running. As planned, 2.1 will be a feature release with some cool stuff. You can also browse
       our repository or even checkout the source yourself from the public SVN and build any time you like.
      </p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            <link href="http://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/incubator/ibatis/trunk">Browse the iBATIS Source Code</link>
          </li>
        </ul>
		</section>

	  <section>
		  <title>iBATIS.NET DataAccess 1.5.0 and DataMapper 1.1.0 are Available</title>
		  <p>
		  (12 Jan 2005) Alpha distributions of iBATIS.NET DataMapper 1.1 and DataAccess 1.5 are available at the <link href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=109704">SourceForge site</link>.
		  This is not an ASF release, but it is under the Apache License.
		  For more, see the <link href="http://sourceforge.net/forum/forum.php?forum_id=437027">release notes</link>.
		  </p>
		</section>


		<section>
			<title>iBATIS/Java 2.0.9 is Available -- Happy New Year!</title>

					<p>(05 Jan 2005) Distributions of iBATIS 2.0.9 are available at the 
					<link href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=61326">SourceForge site</link>.
		      This is not an ASF release, but it is under the Apache License.
					</p>
					
					<p>					
              Well, it's been a long time since we've released any major 
              features. We've been working on stabalizing the platform, organizing 
              the team and supporting the community. We like to consider this 
              progress, but sometimes we want is features. So here we go! Check 
              out the new feature list:
          </p>

            <ul>
              <li><strong>Solution for N+1 selects for 1:M and 
                M:N.</strong> Version 2.0 was always designed for this, I just 
                didn't have a chance to implement it, until now. It's made possible 
                by two small additions to the mappings 
                <ul>
                  <li>&lt;resultMap...groupBy=&quot;prop1,prop2&quot;&gt; </li>
                  <li>&lt;result...resultMap=&quot;subResultMapForCollectionItems&quot;&gt;</li>
                </ul>
              </li>

              <li><strong>Remappable result sets!</strong> So, 
                you're one of those people who wants to use a dynamic SELECT clause 
                in your SQL Maps? Now you can. One simple addition to your select 
                statements. 
                <ul>
                  <li>&lt;select...remapResults=&quot;true&quot;&gt;</li>
                </ul>
              </li>
              
              <li><strong>Isolation Level Support. </strong>Now 
                you can specify the transaction isolation level when starting 
                a transaction. Simply specify it as a parameter of SqlMapClient.startTransaction 
                (int isolationLevel).</li>

              <li><strong>SQL Fragment Includes.</strong> No more 
                repeated where clauses. If you have a need to repeat (such as 
                a count * and a column list version of a query), now you can include 
                the common part of the statement. Simply declare an &lt;sql&gt; 
                element with an id, then &lt;include&gt; it with a refid. You 
                can also use dynamic SQL, inline parameters and anything else 
                you can put in any other statement. Two new elements: 
                <ul>
                  <li>&lt;sql id=&quot;someSqlToInclude&quot;&gt; ... WHERE BLAH 
                    = BLAH ...&lt;/sql&gt;</li>

                  <li>&lt;include refid=&quot;someSqlToInclude&quot;/&gt;</li>
                </ul>
              </li>

              <li><strong>Default CLOB/BLOB Handlers.</strong> 
                Why punish everyone with a good database driver? We've now included 
                default LOB handlers for byte[] and large strings. Any mapping 
                to byte[] with BLOB or LONGVARGBINARY will use the BLOB handler; 
                and any mapping to String with CLOB or LONGVARCHAR will use CLOB. 
                Only poor database drivers are not supported, and may still require 
                a custom tag handler. In those cases, you can use the default 
                ones as an example (they're implemented as CTH).</li>

              <li><strong>Other features include: </strong>TopLink 
                DAO template and TX manager, support for directly implementing 
                TagHandler interface (in place of CTH), a completely refactored 
                XML parser and a few minor bug fixes.</li>

              <li><strong>Documentation coming soon.</strong> 
                &quot;Yeah right!&quot;, you say! Well, admittedly we have been 
                slow to document lately. Now we have a solution for keeping up 
                with ourselves. Our<strong> Wiki </strong>will serve as a documentation 
                launch pad where everyone (including us) can contribute to the 
                documentation of the new features. Good documentation will be 
                promoted to the developer guide. </li>
            </ul>
		</section>

		<section>
			<title>iBATIS/Java 2.0.8 available</title>
			<p>
				(26 Nov 2004) Under the new release plan, Team Java will be alternating between bug fix releases and feature releases. Version 2.0.8 is a bug fix release, and therefore the next release will be a feature release. This approach will keep the product stable while offering power users access to new features earlier and on a more consistent release schedule.
			</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Probes now always return true for hasReadable/hasWriteable property checks.</li>
				<li>Fixed OUT/INOUT parameters to proc not retrieved properly (ibatis-12)</li>
				<li>Verified missing columns throw an exception (ibatis-16)</li>
				<li>Completely $supplied$ SQL statements are not supported (ibatis-17)</li>
				<li>Verified parameter type handlers are applied (ibatis-ll)</li>
				<li>Fixed cache model size of 1 disables caching (ibatis-7)</li>
				<li>Fixed LRU cache memory leak (ibatis-1)</li>
				<li>Added commitRequired attribute to transactionManager to force commit even on query (ibatis-10,3)</li>
			</ul>
			<p><link href="http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/ibatisdb/iBATIS_DBL-2.0.8.470.zip?download">Download 2.0.8</link></p>
		</section>
	
		<section>
			<title>New version of sql2ibatis available</title>
			<p>
				(26 Nov 2004) Alex Egorov has released a new version of his iBATIS configuration and SQL generation tool. It generates configuration files and SQL based on an input DDL file. Check it out. 
			</p>
			<p>
				<fork href="http://alxeg.narod.ru/ibatis/index.html">Download sql2ibatis</fork>
			</p>
		</section>

	 	<section>
     <title>Updated Chinese Document</title>
     <p>(16 Nov 2004) Huge thanks to Liutao for completely translating the entire Java SQL Maps documentation and tutorial to Chinese!</p>
     <p><link href="http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/ibatisdb/iBATIS-SqlMaps-2_cn.pdf?download">SQL Maps Guide</link> | <link href="http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/ibatisdb/iBATIS-SqlMaps-2-Tutorial_cn.pdf?download">SQL Maps Tutorial</link></p>
	  </section>
	
		<section>
     <title>Happy Halloween from iBATIS and The Apache Software Foundation</title>
     <p>(31 Oct 2004) iBATIS has been voted into the Apache Incubator, and a number of resources have been set up. Over the next few weeks, we'll be switching over our current SourceForge resources over to Apache. </p>
    </section>
  
	</body>
</document>